KEN THA

kkt@post.com | (626) 241-5226

SUMMARY

IT professional with over 10 years of experience in tier III escalation support, analysis, implementation, integration, , project management of various network technologies for professional to global enterprise environments which includes proficiency in routing, switching, security, voice, wireless and data center technologies.

TECHNICAL CERTIFICATIONS & SKILLS

•	Certified WAN Professional	CWP	
•	Certified WAN Enterprise Administrator	CWEA	
•	Cisco Data Center Administrator	CDCA	
•	Cisco Voice Administrator	CVA	
•	Cisco Security Administrator	CSA	
•	Cisco Wireless Technician	CWT	
•	Cisco Certified Design Associate	CCDA	
•	Cisco Certified Network Associate – Routing/Switching	CCNA – R/S	

TECHNICAL SKILLS DETAIL

Network Hardware:	Cisco Routers (3900, 2900, 1900, 800), Cisco Catalyst Switch (6500, 5500, 4900, 4500, 3000,
	3100), Cisco Nexus 5k and 7k Series, Cisco ASA 5505/5506 Series, Cisco WLC, F5 LB.
Routing/Switching:	WAN, LAN, TCP/IP, Spanning Tree, BPDU, CDP, Frame-relay, PPP, ACL, Network Address
	Translation (NAT), Port Address Translation (PAT), Access Control List, RIP, OSPF, EIGRP,
	BGP, MPLS, VTP, SNMP, SMTP, ARP, TCP, UDP, Static Routing, Stub Routing, VLAN
	Trunking, Multi-Area OSPF, VLAN, VTP, HSRP, SVI, CEF, Etherchannel, Portfast.
Voice Technologies:	Computer Telephony Integration (CTI), VoIP, CUCM, PoE, H.323,
Security Technologies:	AAA, IPS/IDS, TACACS+, RADIUS, SSH, VPN, Cisco ACS, Data Loss Prevention, IPSec,
	Data Management Zone, Pretty Good Protection (PGP), Public Key Infrastructure (PKI),
	Internet Key Exchange Policy, Port Security, IPS/IDS.
Wireless Technologies:	IEEE 802.1x & 802.11 a/b/g/n/ac, WLAN, WAP, AP, SSID, LWAPP, CSMA/CA, Bluetooth,
<u> </u>	HomeRF, MMDS, LMDS, Aironet, CCK, DSSS.
Monitoring Tools/Hardware:	CCP, VMware, Solar winds, F5, Cisco Works, LogicMonitor, Cisco Security Manager Suite,
~	DNS Servers, DHCP Servers, NTP Server, TFTP Server, Exchange Server, Blade Servers, Web
	Servers, Syslog, FTP, SFTP.

SUMMARY OF PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Shur-Net Managed Services	Field Engineer	2017-Present
ASI-NETWORKS	Systems Engineer	2010-2017
Cross Mortgage	Realtor/Loan Consultant	2006-2010
Prudential Realty	Realtor/Loan Consultant	2001-2006
Ameriquest Mortgage	Sr. Systems Engineer	2005-2006
IndyMac Bank	Sr. Systems Analyst	1999-2005
Triton Pacific Capial, LLC	Network Administrator	1999-2000
IndyMac Mortgage Holdings, Inc	Help Desk Support Analyst	1998-1998

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science Degree in Management in Information Systems	California State University
Certification Program in UNIX & Networking	California State University
Certified WAN Professional Program	LANWAN Professional

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE DETAIL

- Troubleshooting PC/MAC issues
- Troubleshooting general network infrastructure problems, including networking equipment, printers, PC/Server hardware, etc.
- Troubleshooting server hardware issues at our clients' site
- · Visiting customer sites to work on things that cannot be handled remotely
- Learning about and applying proven and emerging technologies (Windows Server, Exchange, SharePoint, Office 365, etc.)

ASI-NETWORKS (Cisco Partner)

Systems Engineer

2010 - December 2017

- Major duties were team management, I.T resource procurement and collaboration with Server administrators.
- J Work as part of a team on the overall operation and support of the Advanced Technologies and Development Department with focus on improving current IT infrastructure in order to accommodate towards ongoing business needs and future growth.
-) Configure, maintain and troubleshoot Cisco devices within production as well as lab environments.
- J Implemented site to site VPN using ASA 5520 and Cisco gateway.
- J Configured and Installed new Catalyst Switches .
-) Managed Integration of new VLAN for additional departments along with relevant documentation and provide assistance with ongoing maintenance and troubleshooting.
- J Configured the details provided by Network Architect to client site equipment with collaboration from on site System and Network Administrators and NOC Engineers.
- J Resolve escalated trouble tickets in Connectwise and provide training/counseling to tier 1 level support specialists.
- J Support technical issues involving Datto backups, Intermedia email relay services.
-) Conduct ongoing research towards new and emerging technologies and provide necessary recommendations during departmental meetings.
-) Proactively engage in additional training using Cisco technologies to maintain progression towards technical development.

KT Homes & 3G Realty

Investor/Consultant

2006-2010

- Real Estate sales and investments
- Land Development

Ameriquest Mortgage Co.

Sr. Systems Engineer

2005-2006

- Responsible for overseeing, implementing, and maintaining various hardware and software technologies in professional, enterprise server environment.
- Collaborate with project managers, departments, and vendors to develop and execute accurate, detailed implementation of mission critical projects.
- Implemented, managed, and constructed large server/client data center consolidation project given timesensitive restrictions along with multiple server development and test environments.
- Designed, apply, and maintain company server infrastructure to optimize network and systems requirements.
- Installed, configured and maintained server securities including firewalls and anti-virus software to ensure proper operations.
- Directed, trained, and managed multiple priorities for junior technical staff while mentoring staff to maintain a high moral.

IndyMac Bank

Sr. Systems Analyst

1999-2005

- Installed, configured, and supported multiple user accounts and network infrastructure utilizing various enterprise applications.
- Installed, upgraded, and monitored server software packages, system security settings, and server clusters to generate reports, analysis, and evaluations of systems and workstations.
- Monitor, troubleshoot, and maintain various hardware technologies including switches, hubs, routers, and remote servers.

J	Installed, designed, and implemented internal/external web portals and deployed new software releases into QA and production servers.	ı, staging
	and production servers.	

Developed, implemented, and monitored Disaster recovery planning strategies to preserve all mission critical accounts, services, and developments of the company.

Triton Pacific Capial, LLC

Network Administrator

1999-2000

- Maintained, monitored, and evaluated company LAN infrastructure generating detailed reports of daily, weekly, and monthly activity.
- Utilized various LAN/WAN technologies to maintenance network efficiency and evaluate systems performance.
- Analyzed, documented, and advised on all network technologies to enhance communications and connectivity.

IndyMac Mortgage Holdings, Inc.

Help Desk Support Analyst

1998-1998

- Provided remote technical and escalations support to various clients and customers on desktop technology solutions, procedures, and repairs.
- Responsible for troubleshooting various hardware technologies, software technologies, network printers, and other peripherals.
- Proficient understanding of multiple technologies critical to providing effective assistance for high profile clients.